Inventory of the Ukrainian Pictorial Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Ukrainian Pictorial Collection
1989-2004
91104
1 manuscript box, 20 envelopes 2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs of various scenes from Ukraine, and especially of demonstrations for Ukrainian independence, and of Ukrainian government officials and governing bodies in session.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Nationalism--Ukraine--Pictorial works.; Ukraine--Pictorial works.
Container List
- 1 print of a Ukrainian independence demonstration in Kiev, January 21, 1990. (File *mA)
- 32 prints of scenes of a Ukrainian independence demonstration in Kiev, January 21, 1990, and meetings in the Rukh Congress Hall. (File B-C)
- 21 prints of Ukrainian independence demonstrations and election rallies, January-March 1990. (File D)
- 8 prints of a burial procession of former Ukrainian political prisoners, November 19, 1989. (File E)
- 29 prints of the damaged Chernobyl Nuclear Plant and demonstrations against operations at the plant, 1991-1992. (File F)
- 22 prints of a meeting of Ukrainian nationalists, January 28, 1992. (File G)
- 46 prints of Ukrainian civil demonstrations, religious ceremonies, and clergy of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church, 1990. (File H)
- 43 prints of Ukrainian government congresses and meetings, 1990. (File I)
- 167 prints of Ukrainian civil demonstrations, 1990-1992. (File K-P)
- 54 prints of Ukrainian government congresses and meetings, and 1992. (File Q-R)
- 71 prints of Ukrainian government officials, including Leonid Kravchuk, 1991-1992. (File S-T)